So we added the backdrop, we added the logic to get rid of the sideDrawer, the next step is to implement
Dolaysyla, kenardan kurtulmak iin mant dzenlediimiz zemin vard ya da bir sonraki adm, bu
this toggle button here.
gei dmesini buraya uygulamaktr.
So to implement some component which allows us to click on and which will then trigger something which
Bu yzden, tklamamza izin veren ve sonra hangisinin karar vermeyeceini gsteren bir
shows the sideDrawer. Now, this is a good exercise for you,
eyi tetikleyecek baz bileeni uygulamak sizin iin iyi bir altrmadr.
it of course involves a couple of steps and there certainly is more than one way of achieving this
Tabii ki birka adm ierir ve kesinlikle buna ulamak iin birden fazla yol vardr.
but feel free to try this on your own either by not creating a component and simply hooking up this
oluturmayn ve bu dev'i bir tklama dinleyicisi ile balayn; daha kolay rota almak veya
div with a click listener to take the easier route or outsource this into its own component, maybe create
bunu kendi bileenine d kaynak olarak atmak belki bir hamburger oluturabilir ve tklanabilir hale getirebilirim. bitirmek, bir
a hamburger icon there, make it clickable and in the end make sure that you somehow get to the layout component
ekilde dzen bileenini elde ettiinizden ve bu tr ovlarn ok geree doru ekilde ayarlandndan emin olun.
and adjust the state to set showSideDrawer to true.
Ancak, bunu kendi banza deneyerek ekinmeyin ya bir bileen
Set it to false initially here then and make sure that you now can somehow click something in the toolbar,
Bata Dearden olmak zere false olarak ayarlayn ve ara ubuundaki bir eyi imdi bir ekilde tklayabildiinizden emin olun.
set the state here as I just said and therefore change open, the open property of the sideDrawer because
Sahne alann burada gsterildii gibi ayarlayn ve yan kapda ak mlkiyetini deitirin,
it's dependent on the showSideDrawer state.
nk yan taraftaki kap durumuna baldr.
Now this is a good practice,
imdi iyi bir uygulamadr.
I'll give you a couple of seconds to post the video and try this on your own and then I'll show you
Videoyu yklemek iin birka saniye
my approach.
vereceim ve bunu kendi banza deneyip sana yaklamm gstereceim.
So were are you successful?
yleyse nerde baarl buluyorsunuz?
Let's now solve it together
imdi birlikte zmleyelim.
but I really urge you to try it on your own
Fakat gerekten kendi banza denemenizi neririm.
first. We want to make sure that we can click this menu button in the toolbar and I want to outsource menu
lk nce ara ubuunda bu men butonuna basabiliriz ve kendi bileenine men dna kurmak isterim;
into its own component which I want to also style as a hamburger icon. I'll place this component in the
bunu da bir hamburger gibi stil etmek istiyoruz. TM bu bileeni site sprgesi klasrnde
sideDrawer folder because it belongs to the sideDrawer and I will name it drawerToggle, in there I'll add
yer alabilir nk yan ekmeceyi kullanacam ve bir js dosyasnda bir ekmece geii eklemek
a drawerToggle.js file.
zere bir karakter deitirme ad vereceim.
This will be a simple component as most of our components are a function which receives props and returns
Bileenlerimizin ou sahne alan ve baz GSX dndren bir ilev olduu iin bu basit
some jsx
bir bileen olacaktr.
and for that of course we need to import react from react. Then I'll export this
Ve elbette yeniden hareket etmeyi tekrar uygulamamz gerekir; bu durumda tm ihracat yaplr.
as a default,
Varsaylan olarak.
so export drawerToggle is a default
Dolaysyla, da aktarma brakma hedefi bir varsaylan deerdir.
and for now I'll simply add the div with the text menu here
Ve u an iin sadece metin mensyle yaptn eyi buraya ekleyeceim.
but I will change this as I just said, I will change this to a hamburger icon in the future.
Ancak bunu, gelecekte yapabileceim bir hamburgere dntreceimi sylediim gibi deitireceim.
For now let's use that though,
imdilik bunu kullanalm.
so make sure to save that drawerToggle file and then move to the toolbar file and import it. Import
ie aktarlan ie aktarma izgisini ektiinizden veya ekmece gei klasrnden ve ekmeceden ie
drawerToggle from imported from the sideDrawer folder, from the drawerToggle folder and drawerToggle.js
aktarlm sedandan veya klasre gei yapn, sandalyeler der ve bu yer tutucuyu kendiliinden kapanla deitirin. ekmece Tauriel bileeni.
file and replace this placeholder here with the self-closing drawerToggle component.
Dolaysyla ekmece toggle dosyasn kaydettiinizden ve daha sonra ara ubuu dosyasna gidin ve
Now the goal is to add a click listener to the div here, so I'll add on click
imdi hedef, tklayarak bunu eklerseniz, gne tklama dinleyicisi eklemektir.
and I then want to bind this to some property which I expect to receive, the click property which should
Ve bunu, her zaman olduu gibi bir tklamayla altrlmas gereken yntemi
as always in this case hold a reference to the method which should get executed on a click.
referans alan bu tklama zellii almay umduum baz mlklere balamak istemedim.
So now in the toolbar component, let's add that clicked property to the drawerToggle and there of course
imdi ara ubuu bileeninde, tklanan mlk izmeye veya deitirmeye ekleyelim ve
we also don't have that method defined in here but we will use the toolbar in the layout component where
elbette burada tanmlanan metoda sahip deiliz, ancak bu yntemi ekleyeceimiz yer ayrma bileeninde
we will add this method.
ara ubuunu kullanacaz.
So ultimately we'll set some property on the tool bar and passed down the method reference from there.
Sonuta, ara ubuunda baz mlkler ayarladk ve orada Mefford referansn getik.
So let's expect this property to be set in the tool bar and I'll name it
yleyse, bu mlkn ara ubuunda ayarlanmasn bekleyelim ve ben bunu isimlendireceim.
drawerToggleClicked,
ekmeceyi ek toplayn toplamak.
this will be a prop I'll receive which holds a reference to the method which should get executed,
Bu, uygulanmas gereken yntemi referans alan bir alc veya alc olacaktr.
so drawerToggleClicked.
Sohbet edip toplayn.
With that,
Bundan.
let's go to layout component and there I'll add the
Bileeni hazrlamaya gidelim ve hepsi yan ekmecede.
sideDrawerToggleHandler
leci deitirin.
Now it actually will work as a toggle
imdi aslnda gei olarak alacak.
so from open to close and the other way around
Yani aktan kapansa ve dier taraftan.
but in our app, we will never be able to see that close functionality because the sideDrawer will overlap it,
Ancak bir saatlik Abu, yakn ekim ilevini gremeyecek, nk site ekilebilirlii akyor.
I'm still going to create it in this way because if we ever were to add this toggle in some other place
Hl bu ekilde kaplamaya devam edeceim nk eer bu geie hi baka bir
in the app, it would really work as a toggle.
yerde NEAP eklersek, gerekten herkes iin alacakt.
Now anyways here, I now as I just said
imdi her neyse burada dedim gibi biliyorum.
want to toggle the displaying state
Bu durumu gsteren tm olaylar konumak istersiniz.
of the sideDrawer. So we can call this.state and now set showSideDrawer to what it's currently not, to
Offsider ya da ylesine biz-ebilmek ses bu devlet ve imdi ayarlamak yan kap olarak ne u anda deil de gsterir.
not this.state.showSideDrawer. So if showSideDrawer is true,
Bu aamada serseri ov tarafnda gsterilmez veya dorudur.
it will now be set to false and the other way around. This approach here has a flaw though,
imdi sahte olarak ayarlanacak ve bu yaklamn br ucunda bir kusur var.
do you see which? I mentioned earlier that if you plan on using the state, insert state, you shouldn't do
Daha nce bahsettiime inanyor musunuz, devlet insets devletini kullanmay planlyorsanz bunu byle yapmamanz gerekir,
it like this because due to the asynchronous nature of set state, this may lead to unexpected outcomes.
nk sz geen Devletin ezamansz doas nedeniyle beklenmedik sonulara yol aabilir.
So instead use the function form, expect the previous state as input and in there, simply return the object
Bunun yerine, beklediim bir nceki durumu ilevini kullann; buna yeni bir durum olarak ayarlamak istediiniz
you want to set as a new state or you want to merge into the state
nesneyi dndrdnzde veya duruma gemek istiyorsanz.
I should say. And of course therefore in there, you don't access this.state but you use the previous state
Ben sylemeliyim ve elbette Devar orada bu duruma eriemiyorsunuz, ancak otomatik olarak
you get passed into this function automatically.
ilev bozukluuna getiiniz nceki durumu kullanyorsunuz.
This is the clean way of setting the state when it depends on the old state.
Bu, eski devlete bal olduunda devletin kurulmas iin temiz bir yoldur.
Now we have a secure way of toggling that and changing showSideDrawer,
imdi, bunu ve geii gsteren yan ekmeceyi deitirmenin gvenli bir yolumuz var.
now of course we want to call these and we should pass it as a reference to the toolbar now because
imdilik bunlar armak istiyoruz ve bunu ara ubuuna bir referans olarak iletmeliyiz, nk
in the toolbar, we're expecting this drawerToggle click property which holds a reference to the method
ara ubuunda, geie tklandnda yrtlecek olan yntemi referans alan tklama
which should get executed when the toggle is clicked.
zelliine doru saklamay umuyoruz .
So let's use that in the layout component here on the toolbar, drawerToggleClicked was the property name
imdi bunu dzen bileeninde ara ubuunda kullanalm tkland jar tklamas bir zellik adyd
and let's pass a reference to the newly created sideDrawerToggleHandler
ve yeni oluturulan siteye veya gei yrtcsne bir referans geelim.
and as always, never execute this method just pass a reference.
Ve her zaman yrtlemedii gibi bu yntem sadece referans gnderir.
Make sure to save all files
Tm dosyalar kaydettiinizden emin olun.
now, let's go back to the application and let's take Manu and indeed it slides in, backdrop removes it
imdi uygulamaya geri dnelim ve Manue'y alalm ve gerekten de slaytlar slaytlar eklinde kaldralm
and we can go back and forth.
dedi ve ileri geri gidebiliriz.
So this is working,
Yani bu alyor.
that's pretty cool.
Bu olduka haval.
Let's now turn this boring not so pretty menu text here into a hamburger icon in the next lecture.
imdi bu skc deil men metnini bir sonraki konumada yapabileceim bir hamburgere evirelim.